digitalpassport.org 2014-06-04

# Privacy Policy | Digital Passport

DIGITAL PASSPORT PRIVACY POLICY

Effective Date: April 12, 2012

Common Sense Media’s Digital Passport collects personally identifiable information from educators when they sign up to join our site. Digital Passport does not collect personally identifying information directly from children. Educators upload information about their students, which our website uses to generate logins for the students. Only the educator who entered the data for a student can view the data of that student. Digital Passport does not collect data from any other third parties, including parents, as this site is intended for use only by educators and their students.

I. Digital Passport

Welcome! Below you will find the privacy policy for Digital Passport. We are dedicated to protecting your privacy and handling any personal information we obtain from you with care and respect. This Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) is designed to answer your questions regarding how we collect, protect, use and share information obtained through the Digital Passport website at [www.digitalpassport.org](http://www.digitalpassport.org/ "www.digitalpassport.org") (the “Site”). As used in this Policy, Common Sense Media and any and all affiliated or contracted entities which may perform certain of the services provided on this Site are collectively referred to herein as “we,” “us” or “our”. We hope this information increases your confidence in Common Sense Media and Digital Passport and enhances your experience on our Site.

Please see our separate Terms of Use, which governs the use of the Site. We encourage you to read this Policy before using the Site, and not to use the Site if you disagree with any part of this Policy. By using this Site or in registering as an educator user, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this Policy.

From time to time, this Policy may be changed, expanded or amended, and may include the introduction of additional provisions. Any changes to this Policy may be made without notice and will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site, so please be sure to review it on a regular basis. The effective date appearing at the top of this page indicates when the latest changes were made to this Policy.

The Site is controlled and operated by a nonprofit organization in the United States, and is not intended to subject Common Sense Media or any affiliated entity to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. We may limit the Site’s availability, in whole or in part, to any person, geographic area or jurisdiction we choose, at any time in our sole discretion.

II. What Data Do We Collect?

In this Policy, when we use the term “Personally Identifiable Information”, we mean any information that can be used to identify or contact a specific individual, such as the individual’s name, postal address, email address and telephone number.  
Educators. Digital Passport collects Personally Identifiable Information from educators when they sign up to join our site. This includes data such as name, email address, school information, and school affiliation.

Children’s Data. Digital Passport does not collect personally identifying information directly from children. Educators upload information about their students, which our website uses to generate logins for the students. Educators and schools are responsible for making sure they have permission from the students’ parents or guardians to do so. Parents should contact their schools and their educators, and refer to school policies about how student information is handled. This Policy does not apply to how schools collect, use or share student information.

Information Collected Through Technology. We may also collect certain information automatically when you visit the Site, such as the browser you are using (e.g., Internet Explorer 8.0, Mozilla Firefox 7.0, etc.), the internet address from which you linked to our Site, the operating system of your computer (e.g., Microsoft Windows), the unique IP address of the computer you used to access our Site and usage and browsing habits. We use this information to administer and improve your experience on our Site, to help diagnose and troubleshoot potential server malfunctions, and to gather broad demographic information.  
To help make sure you receive information that is relevant to you, our Site uses data “cookies.” These cookies are small data files stored on your computer which identify you as a previous visitor to the Site. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. You can instruct your browser not to accept cookies. However, if you disable this function, you may not be able to use some of the features on our Site.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information. Non-Personally Identifiable Information is aggregated information, demographic information and other information that does not reveal a person’s specific identity. We may collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information (e.g., geographic location, zip codes, etc.) when you voluntarily provide such information to us. Such information constitutes Non-Personally Identifiable Information because, unless combined with your name or other Personally Identifiable Information, it does not personally identify you or any other user.

Additionally, we may aggregate Personally Identifiable Information in such a manner that the end product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site. For example, we might use Personally Identifiable Information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular zip code. Such aggregate information is considered Non-Personally Identifiable Information for purposes of this Policy.

III. How Do We Use This Data?

We use Personally Identifiable Information to process requests made through our Site, such as requests to receive our e-newsletters, and to operate the Digital Passport Site. You may opt-out of receiving our e-newsletters at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of all newsletters or by visiting commonsense.org/contact and sending this request using our online form.

Fulfillment of Requests. We may use Personally Identifiable Information about you to fulfill the purpose for which such information was provided (e.g., to help an educator manage a set of students using the Site).

Internal Operations and Analysis. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information about you for our internal business purposes, such as data analysis, audits and so forth. 

Additional Communications. If you register to become a user of our Site or sign up to receive one of our e-newsletters, we may use the Personally Identifiable Information submitted in connection with your application to contact you with surveys or important communications regarding Common Sense Media.

Use of Student Data. Only the educator who entered the data for a student can view that data. Educators can use this feature to track their students’ progress on the Digital Passport system. We never share individual student data with anyone other than the educator who entered that data. We may use and share aggregate student data, such as how many students have earned badges within Digital Passport. Employees of Common Sense Media may access student data for operational purposes including troubleshooting Site issues.

Use of Technology-Derived Information. We use information collected via cookies and other technologies for purposes of Site authentication. We may also use this information to help diagnose and troubleshoot potential server malfunctions and to gather broad demographic information.

Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information. Because Non-Personally Identifiable Information does not personally identify you, we may use or disclose such information for any purpose. For instance, we may compile and share aggregate data about the ages, geographic locations or other demographics of our users, provided that this information does not personally identify any of these users.

IV. How We Share Information Collected On The Site

Educators’ and Students’ Data. We may share educators’ data with their school districts and with state or federal departments of education under certain circumstances, such as to confirm which educators have signed up to use the Site and which features of the Site have been most commonly used. We may also share data provided by teachers and generated by their students (e.g., performance data derived from the use of Site features), but only in aggregate form, with financial supporters of Digital Passport or Common Sense Media, with academic or other researchers and with news media. 

Third Party Service Providers. We work with third parties who provide services such as data analysis, donation processing, infrastructure provision, information technology services, email delivery services, market research and other similar services. We may share Personally Identifiable Information about you with third parties solely for the purpose of enabling these third parties to provide these services. These service providers are given access to Personally Identifiable Information needed to perform their functions, but are restricted from using the Personally Identifiable Information for purposes other than providing services for us.  
Aggregate Data. We may share aggregated data collected via cookies or other technologies with any vendors contracted to maintain the Site. Aggregated data also may be shared with our Board of Directors, funders and partners for various reasons, such as understanding how to increase the effectiveness of our services and the traffic and trends occurring on the Site.  
Law Enforcement; Emergencies; Compliance. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Policy to the contrary, we reserve the right to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to others as we believe to be appropriate (a) under applicable law, (b) to comply with legal process, (c) to respond to governmental requests, (d) to enforce our Terms of Use, (e) to protect our operations, (f) for assistance in fraud detection and prevention, (g) to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Common Sense Media, you or others, and (h) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

V. Children’s Online Privacy

This Site is not intended to be accessed by children under 13 except as part of the educational experience for which the Site was developed. In any event, children under 13 are not encouraged or allowed to register or to provide information to the Site independently from what is furnished by an educator who has registered with the Site, as described above in part II of this Policy.  
As part of our compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, we do not knowingly collect names or email addresses from children under 13, except for the limited circumstances described below. In the event a child under the age of 13 submits a request or question to us on the Site and identifies his or her age, we may use the child’s email address for the sole purpose of responding to the child’s question on a one-time-only basis. However, we will not use the child’s email address for subsequent contact with the child, and we will delete that address from our records once we have responded. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected Personally Identifiable Information from a child under the age of 13, we will make reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

We recognize that children under the age of 13 may inadvertently give out other Personally Identifiable Information in addition to their email address when contacting us with any requests, questions or concerns they have encountered while visiting the Site. We do not collect or use any such additional Personally Identifiable Information acquired in this manner unless it is necessary for us to respond to the problem or question or concern. We do not divulge any such information to any third parties unless we are required to do so by law, court order or subpoena.

We do not sell or knowingly divulge ANY Personally Identifiable Information from children under 13 to any third parties, unless otherwise required to comply with applicable laws, to comply with a court order or subpoena, to enforce our Terms of Use, or to protect the safety and security of our users and our Site.

Children should check with their parent or guardian before entering Personally Identifiable Information on any website, and we urge parents and guardians to discuss with their kids restrictions regarding the online release of Personally Identifiable Information to anyone they don’t know.

VI. Important Disclosures, Practices And Contact Information

Links. This Site contains links to third-party websites. Linked sites are not under the control of Common Sense Media, Inc. and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the contents of any such linked site, or any link contained in any linked site. We provide such links only as a convenience, and the inclusion of a link on the Site does not imply our endorsement of the linked site. If you provide any Personally Identifiable Information through any such third-party website, your transaction will occur on such third party’s website (not our Site) and the Personally Identifiable Information you provide will be collected by, and controlled by the privacy policy of, that third party. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these websites or any other sites linked to or referenced on our Site. We recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices of any of our partners or any other third parties. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS POLICY DOES NOT ADDRESS THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF OUR PARTNERS OR ANY OTHER THIRD PARTIES.

Security. The information transmitted to our website is protected by HTTPS encryption while in transit. Student information is protected by the password and username of the educator who created the student data. Educators should use adequate, secure passwords to protect this information. 

We have implemented software and hardware security measures, such as firewalls, intended to protect your Personally Identifiable Information from unauthorized access. However, although we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us through or in connection with the Site. Despite our precautions, no system can completely guarantee that there will never be unauthorized access to your Personally Identifiable Information, and your use of the Site indicates that you are willing to assume this risk. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, you must immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us in accordance with the section below entitled “Contacting Us.” Please note that if you notify us by physical mail, this will delay the time it takes for us to respond to the problem.

Updating Your Personal Information. If you are an educator, you can update your Personally Identifiable Information at any time by accessing your account. Only the educator who uploaded student information can update that student’s information. Please note we are unable to update or delete any of your Personally Identifiable Information that has been shared with a third party as permitted in this Policy. Also, please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, and there also may be some residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed. We also reserve the right, from time to time, to re-contact former users of the Site.

Removal of Personal Information. If you decide that you no longer want to be a user of the Site, please contact us, and your profile will be removed from our Site. Personally Identifiable Information and other data that you furnished through the Site may remain in our records, even if you are no longer a user, and can be used by us in accordance with this Policy.

Changes to the Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to change this Policy without notice. Any changes to our Policy will become effective upon our posting of the revised Policy on the Site. Use of the Site following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised Policy then in effect.

VII. Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Policy, or the practices of this Site, please contact us. Or write to us at:  
Privacy Department  
Common Sense Media  
650 Townsend Street, Ste. 435  
San Francisco, CA 94103
